Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets, circa 1860-circa 1970; K0001 Series 4; 18 linear feet (Box 14, Box 11, Box 16, Box 15, Box 10, Box 51, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 18, Box 45, Box 46, Box 49, Box 2, Box 1, Box 53, Box 52, Box 48, Box 6, Box 17, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  - Zionist pamphlets, 1917 - 1932 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    Includes, "Auto-Emancipation," 1932, by Leo Pinsker, "A Jewish State: An Attempt at a Modern Solution of the Jewish Question," 1917, by Theodor Herzl, "The Congress Addresses," 1917, by Theodor Herzl, "The Spiritual Revival," 1917, by Achad ha-Am, "Moses," 1917, by Achad ha-Am, "The Supremacy of Reason," 1935, by Achad ha-Am, "A Call to the Educated Jew," 1941, by Louis D. Brandeis.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1918 - 1936 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    Includes, "To the Jewish Youth," 1928, by Chaim Arlosoroff, "Zionism and Jewish Culture," 1915, by Norman Benwich, "Blue-White Papers," 1935, published by World Union of Zionist Revisionists, "Eretz-Israel for Jewish Tourists," 1922, published by the Department of Trade and Industry, "Poale Zionism: An Outline of its Aims and Institutions," 1918, by I. Zar, "Zionism: Its Theory, Origins, and Achievements," 1919, by Israel Goldberg, "Some Observations on the Policy of the Mandatory Government of Palestine," 1930, by J.H. Kann, "Zionism: Its History and Aims," 1905, by Max Nordau, "Palestine and the British Tax-payer," 1929, published by the Jewish Agency for Palestine, "Short History of Zionism," 1936, by Shoshanna Harris Sankowsky, "Principles of Labor Zionism," 1928, by Solomon Schiller, "Zionism and the Jewish National Home," 1930, by Leo W. Schwarz an james Waterman Wise, "Analysis of Zionism," 1936, by Meir Yaari.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1917 - 1939 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    Includes, "Short History of Zionism," 1939, by Shoshanna Harris Sankowsky, "Poale Zionism," 1918, by H. Fineman, "Principles of Zionism," 1928, by Solomon Schiller, "Essays on Socialist Zionism," 1917, by Nachman Syrkin, and "Hechalutz: New Orientation in Zionism," 1936, by David Ben-Gurion.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1904 - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    Includes, "Theodor Herzl and We," 1929, by Martin Buber and Robert Weltsch, "A Jewish State: An Attempt at a Modern Solution of the Jewish Question," 1904, by Theodor Herzl, "The Congress Addresses of Theodor Herzl," 1917, translated by Nellie Straus, "Zionism: Its History and its Aims," 1905, by Max Nordau, and "Auto-Emancipation," 1935, by Leo Pinsker.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1936 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    Includes, "Great Britain the Jews and Palestine," March 1936, by Samuel Landman, "Revolt by Leave: Being Certain Criticisms on the Anti-Zionist Policy of the Palestine Government," November 1936, by Horace B. Samuel, "Social Forces in Palestine," n.d., by Abraham, Revusky, "Revisionism: A Destructive Force," 1940, published by the Emergency Committee for Zionist Affairs, and "British Imperial Interests in Palestine," 1937, by Herbert Sidebotham.
  - Bound pamphlets regarding Jewish settlement in Palestine, 1936 - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    "Antimalaria and Drainage Work by Jewish Bodies," 1936, published by the Jewish Agency for Palestine, "Jewish Colonisation in Palestine," 1937, by David Horowitz, "Memorandum Submitted to the Palestine Royal Commission on Behalf of the Vaad Leumi, the General Council of the Jewish Community of Palestine," 1936, "A Jew of Palestine," 1936, by Elie Eliachar.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1930 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    Includes, "Restoration of Place-Names in Eretz Israel," 1937, by Jacob A. Arikha, "Land and Destiny," 1939, by Solomon Goldman, "Absorptive Capacity of Palestine: Agriculture," 1937, by N. William Hazen, "Immigration and Prosperity," 1930, by S. Hoofien, "Land Settlement in Eretz Israel," 1937, from an address by Abraham Harzfeld, "The Place of Palestine in Modern Jewish Life," 1937, by Rabbi Milton Steinberg, "The Jordon: A New Frontier of Democracy," n.d., by Ira Eisenstein, "Torah from Zion," 1939, by Eugene Kohn, "The Near East in European Politics," 1937, by Hans Kohn, "Documents Relating to the Balfour Declaration and the Palestine Mandate," 1939, published by the Jewish Agency for Palestine, "What Britain Makes Out of Palestine: A Fallacy Exploded," 1938, by Israel Cohen, "The Palestine Situation Restated," 1931, by Felix Frankfurter, "Revisionism: A Destructive Force," 1940, published by the Emergency Committee for Zionist Affairs, "The Communists in Palestine: The Mufti's Moscow Allies," 1939, by Bezalel Sherman, "The Balance Sheet of Stalinism," n.d., by Willi Schlamm.
  - Bound zionist pamphlets, 1891 - 1917 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    Includes, "Pinsker and His Brochure," 1911, by Ahad Haam (second edition), "A Jewish State in Palestine," 1918, by David Werner Amram, "The Progress of Zionism," 1899, by Herbert Bentwich, "George Eliot as a Zionist," 1899, printed by American Federation of Zionists, "The Political Ideal of the Prophets," 1910, by Israel Friedlaender, "Zionism and the American Spirit," 1917, by Elisha M. Friedman, "The Aims of Zionism," 1899, by R.J.H. Gottheil, "The Epistle of the Hebrews," 1900, by Emma Lazarus, "Zionism: Its History and its Aims," 1905, by Max Nordau, "The Zionist Outlook," 1907, by Max Nordau, "Co-operative Agricultural Colonization in Palestine," 1910, by Franz Oppenheimer, "Palestine and the Jews," 1891, by WM. E. Blackstone, "Reform Judaism and Zionism: An Examination of Dr. David Philipson's Thesis That They are Irreconcilable," 1907, by Max Schloessinger, "The Struggle for the Hebrew Language in Palestine," 1914, published by th eActions Committee of the Zionist Organization, "Ten Years of Zionism," 1907, published by the Zionist Central Bureau, "Zionism: A Jewish Statement to the Christian World," 1907, published by the Federation of American Zionists.
    Folder also includes first edition copy of "Pinsker and his Brochure" by Asher Ginzberg (Ahad Haam), translated from the Hebrew by Henrietta Szold.
  - Maimonides' Creed: Fourteen Lecture-Sermons Delivered from the Pulpit of Congregation B'nai Jeshurun, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Holiday sermons, undated (Box 4, Folder 228)
    Includes, "In Quiet and Confidence: A Sermon for Rosh Ha-shono Eve," by Rabbi David Philipson, "To Know and to Proclaim: A Sermon for Rosh Ha-shono Morning," by Rabbi Solomon B. Freehof, "Penitents on Parade: A Sermon for the Sabbath of Repentance (Shabos Shuvo)," by Rabbi Leo M. Franklin, "Man's Path to Happiness: A Sermon for the First Day of Passover," by Rabbi Isaac M. Wise, "When Moses Sang: A Sermon for the Last Day of Passover," by Rabbi Isaac M. Wise, "The Festival of Consecration: A Sermon for Shovuos," by Rabbi Isaac Marcuson, and "The Seen and the Unseen: A Sermon for Yom Kippur Eve (Kol Nidre)," by Rabbi Edward N. Calisch. Missing pages and front and back covers.
  - Judaism and intermarriage with Christians: Discourse delivered at Temple Beth-El, 11/15/1908 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - On mixed marriage, undated (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Testament of faith: four high holy day sermons, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    Includes, "Unreservedly Jews," "Toward Meaning," Religion for Free Souls" and "Beyond Mechanism."
  - I know you and other sermons delivered on Rosh Hashanah and Yom Kippur, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    Includes, "You're Being Watched," "Courage Judaica," "The Mad Woman of Kiev," and "Ich Ken Eich."
  - Founders' Day Sermon, 03/25/1966 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    The address was delivered during the observance of the 100th anniversary of the Plum Street Temple
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1964 - 1965 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1954 - 1955 (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1951 - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1953 - 1954 (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - Green pastures, psalm XXIII analytically interpreted by Lionel Goitein M.D., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 240)
    Signed by the author. Reprinted from The American Imago, Vol. 13, No. 4.
  - Three tales from talmudic literature, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - Impacts of contemporary life upon Judaism, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - High holiday sermons, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - A selection of sermons, vol. 5, no. 1-8, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - Disorganization-reorganization? A series of high holyday sermons, 06/1971 (Box 4, Folder 245)
  - Let's talk about essentials, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - Anniversary service in commemoration of the hundredth birthday of the Rev. Dr. Kaufmann Kohler, 05/15/1943 (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - Sayings of the fathers, sailors, soldiers and airmen's edition, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 248)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 249)
  - An address by Dr. Emil G. Hirsch at the fifteenth anniversary celebration of Free Synagogue, 04/1922 (Box 4, Folder 250)
  - A set of holiday sermons, 1952 - 1953 (Box 4, Folder 251)
  - Two addresses: the tragic respectability of American extremism and a eulogy of President John F. Kennedy, 1963 - 1964 (Box 4, Folder 252)
  - Religion in the American dream, 05/06/1945 (Box 4, Folder 253)
  - Sermon-review of "the deputy", 03/20/1964 (Box 4, Folder 254)
  - Prayer, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 255)
  - In the cleft of the rock, 10/16/1965 (Box 4, Folder 256)
  - The afterlife in Judaism, 04/26/1968 (Box 4, Folder 257)
  - Me'ah shanah le-huladeto shel Meir Dizengof, 1861-1961 (Box 5, Folder 327)
  - Factors in Jewish survival, undated (Box 5, Folder 258)
    This speech was a Founders Day Address for Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, N.Y.
  - The art of prayer, undated (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - A set of holiday sermons, undated (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Is Judaism an optimistic religion?, undated (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - How to face death: a sermon delivered by Rabbi Philip S. Bernstein at the Yom Kippur memorial service, 10/07/1954 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Study as a mode of worship, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - The social outlook of modern Judaism, undated (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Exhibition of Passover haggadahs from the Judaica collection of the Harvard college library, 03/10/1971 - 04/17/1971 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Catalogue 35, biblioteca Espanola, Portuguesa, Judaica, undated (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Catalogue 11, Angol-Judaica with Americana from the libraries of the late Chief Rabbi Dr. J.H. Hertz, C.H., E.N. Adler and other great collectors, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 267)
    With foreword by Cecil Roth
  - List of publications, 04/1971 (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - Prospectus, 10/1970 (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Microcard catalogue of the rare Hebrew codices, manuscripts ancient prints in the Kaufmann collection reproduced on microcards, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 270)
    Introduced by a lecture of the late Prof. Ignacz Goldziher
  - The Michael M. Zagayski collection of rare Judaica, 03/18/1964 - 03/19/1964 (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Bound catalogues, 1914 - 1937 (Box 5, Folder 272)
    Includes, "A Layman's Jewish Library," compiled by Israel Bettan, D.D., Louis I. Egelson, M.A., and Jacob R. Marcus Ph.D., n.d., "A Scripture Bibliography for the Use of Teachers in Secondary Schools and Bible Students," printed by Nisbet and Co. LTD., 1936, "Akiba Eger Ausstellung," 1937, "Soncino Gesellschaft der Freunde des Judischen Buches E.V.," n.d., "Catalogue of the Printed Books and of the Semitic and Jewish MSS in the Mary Frere Hebrew Library at Girton College, Cambridge," by Herbert Loewe, M.A., 1914, "Check-List of an Exhibition of Judaica and Hebraica Held at the Sterling Memorial Library," compiled by Leon Nemoy, 1933, "Een Keur uit de Handschriften en Boeken," published by Bibliotheca Rosenthaliana, 1919, "Moses Mendelsson-Ausstellung," published by Preussische Staatsbibliothek Judische Gemeinde Berlin, 1929, and "Hebrew Books Published in Harvard," by Harry A. Wolfson, 1932.
  - Rare Judaica, biblica, Hebraica, no. 20, undated (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - Hebrew books exhibited at the Jewish Museum, 01/15/1952 - 01/28/1952 (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - Jewish heritage: a reading list for adults, 11/1966 (Box 5, Folder 275)
  - Judaica: a short title catalogue of the books, pamphlets and manuscripts relating to the political, social and cultural history of the Jews and to the Jewish question, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 276)
    Supplement in the library of Ludwig Rosenberger
  - Catalogue of an important collection of Hebraica and Judaica, no. 21, undated (Box 5, Folder 278)
  - Book list, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 279)
  - Bibliography of Jewish bibliographies, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 280)
  - Americana-Judaica and Hebraica, undated (Box 5, Folder 281)
  - Judaica, catalogue no. 39 and catalogue 40, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 282)
    Catalogue 39 is in English and German. Catalogue 40 is in Hebrew.
  - An exhibition on the occasion of the 40th anniversary of the Hebrew University, 04/1965 (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - Mehlman collection, 04/1972 (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - Bound catalogues no. 24-27, 1941 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 285)
    Catalogues 24 and 26 are in English. 25 and 27 are in Hebrew.
  - The Jew in the Elizabethan world picture, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 286)
  - Specimen of a new edition of the Greek Joshua, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 287)
    Reprinted from the Israel Abrahams Memorial Volume.
  - Royal Hebraists, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 288)
  - The scientific work of some outstanding mediaeval Jewish scholars, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 289)
    Offprint from Essays and Studies in Memory of Linda R. Miller. Signed by the author.
  - Recent literature on Philo (1924-1934), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 290)
    Reprinted from Jewish Studies in Memory of George A. Kohut. Signed by the author.
  - Jewish biblical scholarship in America, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 291)
    Reprint from the Jewish Quarterly Review, vol. 67. Signed by the author.
  - Traditional Judaism and birth control, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 292)
    Reprint from Judaism: A Quarterly Journal of Jewish Life and Thought, vol. 16, no. 2, Spring issue. Inscribed to Rabbi Kiev.
  - The philosophy implicit in the midrash, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 293)
    Offprint from Hebrew Union College Annual, vol. 27. Signed by the author.
  - The Talmud and the medieval papacy, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 294)
    Reprint from Essays in Honor of Solomon B. Freehof. Signed by the author.
  - Among recent acquisitions, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 295)
    Offprint from Studies in Bibliography and Booklore, vol. 4, no. 3. Signed by author.
  - Italy's antisemites, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 296)
    Reprint from Jewish Social Studies, vol. 1, no. 1. Signed by author.
  - Studies in pre-tibbonian philosophical terminology, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 297)
    Reprint from the Jewish Quarterly Review New Series, vol. 17, no. 2. Signed by the author.
  - Who was the first rabbi of Surinam?, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 298)
    From the Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society, no. 5.
  - The trial of Francisco Maldonado de Silva, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 300)
    From the Publications of the Jewish American Historical Society, no. 11.
  - Jewish mystecism, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 301)
    Reprinted from the Harvard Theological Review, vol. 36, no. 2.
  - Proceedings of the Rabbinical Assembly of America, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 302)
    Reprinted from Proceedings of the Rabbinical Assembly of America, vol 24.
  - Bulletin of the American Schools of Oriental Research: supplementary studies, no. 4, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 303)
  - Pre-Maccabean documents in the passover haggadah, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 304)
    Reprinted from the Harvard Theological Review, vol. 36, no. 1.
  - The Jewish factor in Medieval civilization, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 305)
    Reprinted from the Proceedings of the American Academy of Jewish Research, vol. 12.
  - Philo on free will, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 306)
    Reprinted from the Harvard Theological Review, vol. 35, no. 2.
  - The Russian Jew in America, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 307)
    Reprinted from the Publication of the American Jewish Historical Society, vol. 43, nos. 1-2.
  - The minute book of congregations Zur Israel of Recife and Magen Abraham of Mauricia, Brazil, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 308)
    Reprinted from Publication of the American Jewish Historical Society, vol 42, no. 3.
  - The history of the Hebrew Union College, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 309)
    Reprinted from Publications of the American Jewish Historical Society, no. 40, part 1.
  - Hermann Cohen's philosophy of Judaism, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 310)
    Reprinted from Judaism: A Quarterly Journal of Jewish Life and Thought. Signed by the author.
  - On the date of the completion of the Moreh Nebukim, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 311)
    Offprint from Hebrew Union College Annual, vol. 12-13. Signed by the author.
  - Melito of Sardes, the first poet of decide, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 312)
    Offprint from Hebrew Union College Annual, vol. 37. Signed by the author.
  - Der Elfter Tsiyonisten-Kongres, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 313)
    Yiddish
  - The reflex, 01/1928 (Box 5, Folder 314)
  - The reflex, 08/1928 (Box 5, Folder 315)
  - Hagode far gloyber un apikorsim, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 316)
    title from cover: Haggadah shel Pesah (Yiddish)
  - Nashirah Reim: shirim hadashim l'zimrah ba-tsibur ul-makhelah, 1944 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 317)
  - Konstitutsie (grunt-gezets) funem Farband Sovetishe Sotsialistishe Republik., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 318)
  - Bet ha-Sofer ba-ir ha-atikah Yerushalayim, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 319)
  - Ke-hom ha-yom (idilyah), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 320)
  - Erets tsevi: mekhalkel tekhunat kol are Erets ha-Kodesh im temunot ve-tsiyurim ... totsaah Erets tsevi mekhalkel tekhunat kol are Erets ha-Kodesh im temunot ve-tsiyurim totsaah ketsarah meha-sefer "Moreh derekh be-Erets Yisrael ve-Surya., 1899 (Box 5, Folder 321)
    Hebrew and German
  - Collection of Zionistic and national songs. The best and most popular songs of famous poets in Hebrew, English and Yiddish=Kovets shire tsiyon ve-shire am meet meshorerim nodaim., 1903 (Box 5, Folder 322)
    Hebrew, Yiddish and English
  - Elohe Bialik, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 323)
  - Kinor Tsiyon: kovets shirim leumiyim va-amamiyim ha-musharim keha-yom be-khol Erets Yisrael., 1921 - 1922 (Box 5, Folder 324)
  - Sefer ha-likutim: kovets midrashim yeshanim = Sammlung alterer Midraschim und wissenschaftlicher Abhandlungen. Part 3, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 325)
  - Emek ha-bakha = La vallee des pleurs. Prie`res qu'on recite au cimeti`ere, pre`s des malades, des mourants et des morts, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 326)
  - Stinografyah Hadashah le-Ivrit, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 328)
    Hebrew stenography
  - Magazin fr die Wissenschaft des Judenthums: 17 Jahrgang, 1890, Erstes Quartalheft: heft 1 (Box 5, Folder 329)
    I German and Hebrew.
  - Undzer naye konstitutsye, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 330)
  - Harel be-Milhomat Sheshet ha-Yomim, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 331)
  - ha-Galgal, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 332)
    The 1945 victory edition
  - Kevutsat shirim: enthalt Tsiyon un folks-lieder in Hebreish, Idish un English; mit noten = Jewish national and Zion songs.., 1924 (Box 6, Folder 333)
    Hebrew, English and Yiddish
  - Olam ha-sefer, 12/1954 (Box 6, Folder 334)
    Publishers and publishing in Israel
  - Y.L. Perets, kharakter-shtrikhen, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 335)
    Finf niftorim, volume 2
  - Mendele Moykher Sforim: fragmenten vegen zeyn literarisher perzenlikhkeyt, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 336)
    Finf niftorim; volume 3
  - Di natsyonale viederbelebung fun dem Idishen folk fun Pinhas Ben-Ami (P. Rutenberg) oys dem rusishen mansuskript iberzetst fun B. Rivkin, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 337)
  - Der urshprung fun gloybn, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 338)
  - Evreiskii natsional'nii fond, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 339)
    at head of title: Gulat ha-erets.
  - Shirim la-am: bi-shevil shirah be-tsibur 1, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 340)
  - Shirim la-am: bi-shevil shirah be-tsibur 2, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 341)
  - Shirim la-am: bi-shevil shirah be-tsibur 3, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 342)
  - Shirim la-am: bi-shevil shirah be-tsibur 4, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 343)
  - Shirim la-am: bi-shevil shirah be-tsibur 5, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 344)
  - Pirhe aviv ...berakhot ve-agadot., 1901 (Box 6, Folder 345)
  - Ha-gadish, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 346)
    Title page in Hebrew and Russian, text in Hebrew
  - Histadrut ha-ovdim mahi?., 1933 - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 347)
  - Din ve-heshbon shel ha-vaad ha-leumi, Shevat 691-1. Adar 692, hugash la-moshav ha-sheni shel asefat ha-nivharim., 1932 (Box 6, Folder 348)
  - Pirke gemara: perek ha-Meniah (perek shlishi mi-meschta Bava Kama), 1925 (Box 6, Folder 349)
  - Rabbotai nevarekh: Grace after meals, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 350)
    Text in English and Hebrew; unacc. melodies with romanized Hebrew words.
  - Shelilah u-setirah: histaklut, 1909 - 1910 (Box 6, Folder 351)
  - Masa le-Erets-Yisrael bi-shenat 800, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 352)
  - Der Kittel, undated (Box 6, Folder 353)
  - Hok u-mishpat bi-Yisrael bi-shanat ha-shivim, 1980 - 1989 (Box 6, Folder 354)
  - Lemaan Yerushalayim, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 355)
  - 60 folks-lider mit noten gezamelt fun M. Kipnis, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 356)
  - Asia (Asya), 1900 - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 357)
  - Ima poh bishlah daysah ..., 1948 - 1975 (Box 6, Folder 358)
  - Yomim tovim folklor, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 359)
  - Leket midrashim: bo nilketo ve-neesfu midrashim ketanim...va-alehem hearot u-veurim., 1902 - 1903 (Box 6, Folder 360)
  - Di heyrath ferfast und heroysgegeben fun Leonard Landes, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 361)
    missing title page.
  - R. Yehudah ha-Levi u-meshorere bet Alomani, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 362)
  - Al Histadrut ha-Ovdim be-Erets-Yisrael, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 363)
  - Der birger-krig in Frankraykh, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 364)
  - Perush ehad mi-gedole ha-rishonim le-hilkhot ha-Rif im mavo, hearot u-veurim me-et ha-Rav Hayim Dov Shevel, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 365)
    Added t.p. in English: A commentary upon "The laws of Rabbi Isaac Alfasi" to tractate Pesahim by one of the early rabbis of Provence.
  - Piyutim atikim., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 366)
  - Igrot Shir le-Rafael Kirkhhaim, Zekharyah Frankel ve-aherim, 1926 - 1927 (Box 6, Folder 367)
  - Or genuz shel Hazal al darkhe ha-mikra: nashe Hoshea = Biblical interpretation in the light of detached rabbinic texts: "The wives of the prophet Hoshea, 1949 - 1950 (Box 6, Folder 368)
    off-print from TALPIOTH: v. 4: no. 3-4
  - Rashi be-tor paytan, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 369)
  - Collection of Zionist and national songs: the best and most popular songs of famous poets in Hebrew, English and Yiddish collected and published by Joseph Magil., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 370)
    Copy 1 is incomplete and has ownership stamp from Louis I. Newman
  - Hertsl bukh, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 371)
  - Anot: perakim le-shirah be-makhelah uve-tsibur, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 372)
  - Anot: perakim le-shirah be-makhelah uve-tsibur: no 8, 1939 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 373)
  - Yediot: hov. 2, 03/1950 - 04/1950 (Box 6, Folder 374)
  - Yediot: hov. 3, 05/1950 - 06/1950 (Box 6, Folder 375)
  - Yediot: hov. 4, 06/1951 (Box 6, Folder 376)
  - Sefer Ashdot ha-pisgah :hov. 2, kovets 6.: asefat mikhtavim u-maamarim le-Torah u-vikoret ve-hokhmat Yisrael arkhtiv ve-sidartiv, Hilel David ha-Kohen Trivash yekhuneh Ravin; ve-ozer al yadi Avraham Zakhaim, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 377)
  - Hok u-musar ba-mishpat ha-Ivri, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 378)
  - Horaat ha-habaah veha-sifrut be-vate ha-sefer ha-tikhonim: simposyon she-neerakh al yede ha-Universitah ha-Ivrit, 07/1942 (Box 6, Folder 379)
  - Teshuvah be-safah Italkit me-Avraham Gratsiani, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 381)
  - Tazkir ha-Vaad ha-Leumi li-Yehude Erets Yisrael, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 382)
  - Ture Yeshurun, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 383)
  - Meorot: li-melot 750 shanah li-fetirat ha-Rambam, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 384)
  - El Maccabio, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 385)
    text in Hebrew, Ladino, French and Greek